RYAN MCMICHAEL

Ryancmcmichael@yahoo.com | (770) 539-1463 | 6727 Willowbrook Trail, Flowery Branch, GA 30542

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a challenging and rewarding software development role in a dynamic, fast-moving environment where innovation, teamwork, and responsibility are encouraged. I am a motivated, success-driven individual that thrives upon an environment that allows for personal growth and advancement.

KEY SKILLS

Communication – Experience dealing with customers internally and externally through telephone and email, ensuring successful communication by active listening and working proactively.

Problem Solving – Working efficiently to resolve simple and complex issues in a systematic and independent manner; able to find appropriate and high quality resolutions for difficult situations.

Computer Skills – Extensive experience with Java, C++, VBA, C, Ada, web development languages, and Microsoft Office. Database experience with Microsoft 365 Online, Microsoft Access, OpenSQL, MySQL, and Microsoft SQL.

EXPERIENCE

ERP ADMINISTRATOR - CABINETS BY DESIGN, INC.

OCTOBER 2013 - PRESENT

Head of implementation and maintenance of Seradex, a custom-configured ERP software, as well as other custom-configured software.

Create, test, and deploy custom tools to integrate within the ERP system.

Extensive use of Microsoft Excel and Access to build system tools for current processes.

Create and maintain an inventory management system for all building materials.

Manage input from project managers, business owner, and engineering manager to maintain project schedule.

Read and analyze building plans, specifications, and shop drawings to produce accurate production estimates.

Communicate with contractors and project managers to produce takeoffs, estimates, and change orders within predefined time constraints.

Coordinate and conduct weekly production scheduling meetings to ensure product arrives on schedule.

Create shop drawings for products that are then programmed into a CAD/CAM controlled saw.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - WHATSTHE.BUZZ

JANUARY 2017 - MAY 2017

Improved UI for user surveys and owner dashboard for greater user-friendliness.

Leveraged Javascript graphing libraries to display collected data in a concise, understandable manner.

Combined use of PHP and Javascript to update and maintain data in MySQL database.

Used Twitter's Bootstrap framework to enable both web users and mobile users to access the system.

Rapidly prototyped new features to propose to project owner before rolling them out.

Tested and debugged code to ensure a consistent and stable user experience.

Worked closely with other members of development team to ensure that schedules were met and modules worked well together.

PROGRAM SPECIALIST - PAY IT FORWARD SCHOLARSHIPS

JUNE 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2013

Maintained accurate records for donations received and scholarships granted for large-scale nonprofit.

Communicated with customers and schools via phone and email to guarantee customer satisfaction.

Created weekly, monthly, and yearly summary and audit reports using Microsoft Excel.

SHIFT MANAGER - STARBUCKS COFFEE COMPANY

OCTOBER 2010 - DECEMBER 2012

Interviewed, hired, and then trained new employees on proper procedure and customer service.

Managed inventory, ordering, and stocking of products and supplies.

Produced efficient work and time schedules complying with company standards for sales and labor.

SKILLS

Java, C++, VBA, C, Ada, Python, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, MVC, CodeIgniter, Bootstrap, SQL, MySQL, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk AutoCAD, Autodesk Revit, Autodesk Architecture

EDUCATION

KENNESAW STATE UNIVERSITY, KENNESAW, GA

(Bachelors of Science in Computer Science, with Honors) JANUARY 2014 - MAY 2017 3.87/4.00 GPA

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH GEORGIA, GAINESVILLE, GA

(Associates of Science in Engineering, with Honors) AUGUST 2010 - DECEMBER 2013 3.66/4.00 GPA

REFERENCES CHRIS ASKEW

CABINETS BY DESIGN, INC. ENGINEERING MANAGER (404) 580-5498

GREG MILLER

CABINETS BY DESIGN, INC. SENIOR ESTIMATOR (404) 314-1552

JERRY MONCADA

DOOLEY MACK CONSTRUCTION ESTIMATOR (770) 533-2053